<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tech on Jet Villegas</title>
    <link>http://localhost:57141/categories/Tech/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tech on Jet Villegas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 11:41:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:57141/categories/Tech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57141/2022/04/09/jet-villegas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 11:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57141/2022/04/09/jet-villegas/</guid>
      <description>I am a builder, operator, and investor in the technology industry. I’ve worked on many successful commercial and free products: games, tools, runtimes, operating systems, browsers, programming languages, servers, distributed systems, mobile and web applications. I may have code running on your device right now.&#xA;My mission is to advance the human condition via technology. I operate on a global scale with a keen eye for the critical details. If you would like to work with me, I am often hiring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running the Lucene 8.9.0 Demo on Ubuntu 20.04 LTS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57141/2021/07/05/running-the-lucene-8-9-0-demo-on-ubuntu-20-04-lts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 08:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57141/2021/07/05/running-the-lucene-8-9-0-demo-on-ubuntu-20-04-lts/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been teaching people about Search Advertising lately, and I use the Lucene project to demonstrate indexing, searching, relevance, ranking, scoring, and boosting. It’s a little tricky to set up with some gotchas with build and runtime setup. I’m posting here so I can tell students where to look.&#xA;This tutorial assumes a clean Ubuntu Linux 20.04 LTS system. We’ll put developer dependencies into a dev folder on the user’s home directory:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloning Virtual Machines in KVM</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57141/2021/07/04/cloning-virtual-machines-in-kvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 06:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57141/2021/07/04/cloning-virtual-machines-in-kvm/</guid>
      <description>I run many virtual machines on KVM and VirtualBox. I typically clone an existing VM that is already set up for the project or service I’m working on. These are the steps I take on KVM on Linux (Ubuntu) hosts to clone and deploy a guest VM.&#xA;On the host Suspend the VM you’re copying&#xA;sudo virsh shutdown source_VM&#xA;Clone the source VM with a new name&#xA;sudo virt-clone --original source_VM --name destination_VM --file /var/lib/libvirt/images/destination_VM.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Plex Server Migration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:57141/2021/06/27/plex-server-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 12:39:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:57141/2021/06/27/plex-server-migration/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I describe how to migrate media from one Plex server to a new server installation. The official Plex documentation on how to do this leaves out several critical details that I’ll cover here. If you’ve somehow lost the server configuration options from your new install, I’ll show you how to fix that below.&#xA;![](https://jetvillegas.com/wp-content/uploads/sites/5/2021/06/no_server_options-1024x897.png)## Prepare the Source Server I’m moving from one Linux installation (Ubuntu 18.04.5 LTS) to another (Ubuntu 20.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
